Akash Pawar, Senior Software Engineer

Pune, India, 8975974557, pawarakash2000@gmail.com

PROFILE	 2+ years experience in the Salesforce.com both as Administrator and Developer in SFDC Customization Apex, LWC, SOQL, Process Builder, Flows and Lightning Platform. Designing and Developing a solution according to Requirements and platform specific technical best practices. Good Understanding on the salesforce force.com platform. Proficient in grasping new technical concepts and utilizing them in an effective manner.
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY	
Dec 2022 — Present	Senior Software Engineer, Persistent Systems Client - Avid, USA Pund
	 Migration of PSA of Financial Force (Certinia) from classic to lightning. Developing new custom solutions as per the requirements and converting old classic components into lightning. Responsible for deployment process using change sets. Experience in SFDC development using Apex classes and triggers, LWC, SOQL, SOSL. Proficiency in SFDC Administrative tasks like creating Profiles, Roles, Users, Page Layouts, Validation Rules, Reports, Dashboards, Tasks and actions. Experience in data exporting and importing using Import wizard and Apex Data Loader. Developed SFDC customized Reports, Dashboards and Processes to continuously monitor data quality and integrity. Code optimization with governor limits of Salesforce.
Jun 2022 — Nov 2022	Software Engineer, Persistent Systems Internal -EWS Pune
	 Worked on development of early warning system (EWS) which effortlessly track governor limit usage, identify patterns, and receive automated notifications if a governor limit breaches a defined threshold. Developed using LWC, Apex and Chart.js library. Writing test classes for the developed apex code.
EDUCATION	
Jun 2018 — Aug 2022	Bachelor of Technology, Dr Babasaheb Ambedkar Technological University Lonere Raigae
	Completed B Tech degree in Information Technology passed with first class with distinction
CERTIFICATIONS	Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I
	Salesforce Certified Administrator
	Salesforce Certified Javascript Developer I
SKILLS	Apex
	LWC
	SOQL and SOSL
	Flows
	Process Builder
	Force.com Platform

LANGUAGES English Highly proficient Hindi Native speaker

Javascript

 $HTML \ and \ CSS$